Guide to the Morris and Dorothy Margolin film collection, 1947-1982 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Reel 23: TreeTops - Tanzania - Kenya - Safari Club / Safari - Ngorongoro Crater - Durban - Zulu Land, October 1971
  Dorothy with group of locals behind her
  sign: "KENYA / This Sign is on the Equator"
  Dorothy near sign, small market on other side of dirt road
  Morris points to equator sign
  sign: "Welcome to Tanzania"
  landscapes, many with villagers
  city street
  directional signs
  exterior of New Arusha Hotel
  informal roadside market
  sign: "Meru Tavern Bar"
  street scenes, including women carrying bundles on their heads
  Dorothy walks toward camera, lawn chairs and pool nearby, hills and water in background
  exterior of Lake Manyara Hotel
  zebra-painted buses
  back of white car with license plate KLL 65
  entry gate with animal skull on fence
  sign: "Lake Manyara National Park"
  pathway and sign: "Take No Liberties with Dangerous Animals"
  white car and zebra painted buses in lot
  Dorothy walks toward building
  landscapes with animals, including rhino with baby, hyena, flock of birds, lion, jackals, gazelles, wildebeest?, zebras, and others
  sign: "Headquarters / Ngorongoro Conservation Unit"
  a few locals stand along road, one by car -- perhaps at the Conservation Unit?
  Lake Manyara? and environs, including wildlife such as zebras, birds, antelope, gazelles, lioness, buffalo, elephants, and others
  young people approach camera, selling necklaces
  group of tourists with cameras
  children (some naked) run along road, approach camera, hold out hands
  group of naked children dance
  bare-breasted woman selling necklaces
  huts on hillside
  Dorothy exits bus
  flowers and foliage
  group enters Ben's Den
  cheetah or leopard? in the shade
  village and villagers
  bare-breasted women
  Dorothy poses with villagers
  villagers gather, perform
  - Reversal original, Super 8mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (400 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 29:40) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 29:40) (Box 1)
- Reel 24: France, Hungary, 1975
  street scenes in France
  exterior of Hotel Inter-Continental
  man directs traffic, street scenes
  Dorothy across the street, cars whiz past
  exterior of Hotel Meurice, Paris
  golden statue of person on horse
  group plays bocce ball in park
  sidewalk scenes, gardens
  fountain, possibly Tuileries Garden?
  Arc du Carrousel
  statues in park
  exterior of Louvre, close-up on lion statues flanking door
  scenes of the Seine River
  Dorothy on sidewalk, next to yellow vehicle
  priest? standing by lamppost
  dogs playing in park, possibly Jardin du Luxembourg?
  Dorothy sunbathing on deck near pool
  view of ocean, harbor, coastline from pool deck
  pool side bar
  Dorothy reads paper in lounge chair on deck
  skyline, pans to boats in harbor
  views of French? coastline
  Dorothy walks to unidentified building
  signs: "Golfe-Juan / Syndicat d’Initiative" and "Cannes P.T.T."
  Dorothy exist building, walks toward camera
  palm trees and pedestrians along promenade
  close-up on boat: "Komati Southampton"
  Dorothy near gate on dock
  title: "Boats boats boats!"
  close-up on water
  views of coastline, water, ocean liner, sailboat
  beachgoers wade into water, sunbathe on rocks
  views of coastline, water, harbor
  abstract sculpture and mosaic on building
  Dorothy walks out of unidentified building, possibly an art museum?
  artwork in museum, some is underexposed
  sidewalk scene, Dorothy at café
  beach scenes, including nearby promenade
  exterior of Palais des Festivals et des Congres, Cannes
  couple eats at beachside café
  Dorothy exits InterContinental Carlton Cannes
  sign: "Carlton Beach"
  close-up on exterior of unidentified building
  beach scenes, including a number of topless sunbathers
  kids ride bicycles in city square
  pigeons gather around woman with cane seated on bench
  buildings along river? and suspension bridges in Hungary?
  exteriors of building, possibly Buda Castle, under construction
  close-up on lion statue
  exteriors of building under construction
  statue littered with rubble
  pieces of statue on ground
  sign: "Magyar Munkasmozgalmi Muzeum"
  exteriors of building
  statue in city square
  Dorothy talks to a woman in courtyard, kids learn over banister
  close-up: street number “66”
  exterior of Inter-Continental
  scenes of Heroes’ Square, including tour group and uniformed men
  hazy views of Budapest skyline, Danube River
  street scenes, including Dorothy walking with tour group
  sign: "(visual) no dogs"
  Fisherman's Bastion
  Dorothy walks toward unidentified building with woman
  Danube River and buildings on opposite bank
  traffic as seen from tour bus?
  directional sign: "Esztergom, Visegrad"
  cemetery?
  sign: "Autobusz / Panorama / Buszmegallo a Fellegvarhoz / Bushaltestelle Zur Citadelle"
  mountainside, views of rural Danube River
  close-up on ruins on mountaintop
  Dorothy talks to woman on sidewalk
  women sit on bench
  ruins on mountaintop
  Dorothy still talking to woman on sidewalk
  boat pulls away from dock
  structure, possibly ruins, on hillside
  aerial views of countryside
  Dorothy and friends? pose for camera
  Dorothy and friends? walk along rural road
  directional sign, difficult to read
  directional sign: "Etterem Restaurant"
  ruins on hilltop
  sign: "Pilisi Parkerdo, and others"
  aerial view of Danube River
  Dorothy and friends? wander around ruins
  views of countryside
  sign in Hungarian
  small group gathers at roadside
  woman sells wares at small table
  tour bus and tour group in parking lot
  directional sign: "WC"
  fortress on hilltop
  scenes of Danube River
  scenes of Danube River, fortress on hilltop
  directional sign: "Budapest, Esztergom"
  Dorothy sits on bench, smoking
  signs in Hungarian
  small boats on Danube River
  passengers, including Dorothy, on ferry
  views of countryside from river
  man with dachshund on shore
  Dorothy on street in small Hungarian town
  suburban, arguably rural, street scenes
  sign: "Beszallas Budapest Fele"
  sign: "MHRT Nagymaros"
  buildings alone Danube in Budapest
  Dorothy poses for camera
  Budapest street scenes
  - Reversal original, Super 8mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (500 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 33:04) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 33:04) (Box 1)
- Reel 25: Munich - Germany, 1975
  exterior of Hotel Vier Jahreszeiten
  sign: "Nationaltheater"
  National Theater in Munich, Germany
  street scenes, including U-bahn entrance
  traditional Bavarian architecture
  flower market
  street scenes of downtown Munich
  window of butcher shop
  street scenes, including outdoor market
  buildings with Lowenbrau logo
  more scenes from the outdoor market
  sign: "Kartoffel Verkauf (Potato Sale)"
  sign: "Marienplatz / Tal"
  Munich street scenes
  street sign: "Ludwigstrasse"
  sign: "Neue pinakothek / Staatsgalerie moderner kunst"
  statue outside of neue pinakothek
  artwork in neue pinakothek, most underexposed
  exterior of unidentified building, including close-ups on damage
  sidewalk scenes, including group gathered to watch…?
  directional sign: "Olympia-Radstadion, Leichtathletikhalle, Olympiastadion"
  Munich’s Olympic facilities
  sidewalk scenes in Munich shopping district
  glockenspiel at Marienplatz
  sidewalk scenes, including close-up on Hirmer
  Dorothy window-shopping at jewelry store
  sign: "Schmuck Uhren Huber Trauringe"
  more of Munich’s Olympic facilities, including Olympichalle and Olympicstadion
  exterior of Hofbrauhaus
  - Reversal original, Super 8mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (190 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 16:02) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 16:02) (Box 1)
- Reel 26: Romania / Bucharest, Bulgaria / Sofia, Yugoslavia / Zagreb, 1975
  - Reversal original, Super 8mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (400 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 23:20) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 23:20) (Box 1)
- Reel 27: London, July 1976
  Dorothy sitting in stadium with others
  head leaders
  British flag on rooftop, highway in background
  aerial view of city and surroundings
  street scenes, including double decker red buses
  Dorothy walks through gate
  sign: "Knightsbridge Spaghetti House"
  exteriors of Hyde Park Hotel
  The Scotch House / Burberry’s on London corner
  street scene, with Harrod’s in distance
  Dorothy walks along sidewalk, walks into purse shop
  visit to unidentified site, outside of London?
  sunbathers on lawn
  signs for Cafeteria, Ladies
  Big Ben, Palace of Westminster from across the Thames
  Gresham Street, London
  Guildhall
  sign: "Site of Blackwell Hall, 1356-1820"
  interiors of church? including stained glass windows
  Dorothy on street outside of The George Inn
  performance at outdoor theater
  sign: "The Dickens House Library & Museum"
  residential street, sign on building: "Stable Yard"
  sign on building: "Stable Yard"
  Queen’s Guardsman in distance
  Little St. James’s Street, London
  Selwyn House
  views of buildings, rose garden
  sign: "Mariscos"
  Dorothy and couple at café table
  Greenwich Park overlooking London, views of Queen’s House?
  statue at park
  sign: "Prime Meridian of the World"
  Royal Observatory
  exteriors of National Maritime Museum
  River Thames?
  exteriors of unidentified building, possibly Royal Naval College?
  friend pouts and walks toward camera
  Cutty Sark and environs
  Gipsy Moth IV
  friend hams it up for the camera
  Royal Naval College
  restaurant: The Bull at Bisham
  grounds of the Compleat Angler Hotel
  Dorothy and couple at café
  River Thames in Marlow
  George Dragon Hotel, High Wycombe
  street scenes, including British police
  Dorothy and couple walks through gardens
  grounds and exterior of unidentified residence
  sign: "Thames Conservancy NOTICE"
  boats on dock
  family walks along shaded path
  Dorothy and couple along bank of River Thames
  Spread Eagle Hotel and environs
  sidewalk and street scenes in small town
  building: "The Wheatsheaf? Fine Horsham Ales"
  clock tower / rotunda
  bulletin board for Chichester Cathedral
  people at park, pans to street scenes
  Chichester Cathedral, West Sussex?; under renovation
  Horse Guards Avenue, City of Westminster
  posted schedule for changing of the Queen’s Life Guard
  Queen’s Guard
  street scenes, including unidentified building
  more shots of Queen’s Guard; Dorothy approaches guard on horseback
  street scenes in London?
  - Reversal original, Super 8mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (200 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 16:23) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 16:23) (Box 1)
- Reel 28: Rhine River Cruise, Majorca, July 1976
  harbor and other boats (one with German flag), shot from boat
  church on riverbank
  street scenes, blurry signs… one is for Hauptbahnhof
  Dorothy and young woman on sidewalk
  exterior of hotel, name is blurry
  Dorothy and young woman walk toward hotel
  young kids play in fountain
  close-ups of cathedral in Cologne, Germany
  Dorothy and woman near café
  Dorothy boards bus
  people on deck of river boat
  boats (one is labeled 150 Jahre Koln-Dusseldorfer), riverbank from boat
  Dorothy and young woman walk down hallway
  boats, bridges, riverbank shot from boat
  interior of boat, Dorothy and young couple sit at café
  passengers on deck of boat
  flags lowered
  Dorothy and others look out over boat deck
  more scenes from the boat trip
  young girl jumps down steps, art propped up along sidewalk
  building: "Correos Y Telegrafos" (Posts and telegraphs)
  building: "Caja Portal de Amorros"
  sign for Air France
  billboard: "Dinero de verano / Banco de Bilbao"
  scenes of narrow street
  poster: "Maria del mar Bonet"
  man points to words written on wall, Dorothy and young woman nearby
  woman seated on balcony
  aerial view of street scenes
  sign: "La Loza Mallorquina Juan Canals No. 7"
  sidewalk scenes, shops
  boats in small inlet, nearby hotel
  close-ups on boats in inlet
  blurry sign
  docked boats, including large boat: Stena Germanica
  harbor, dock, nearby roads
  passengers on Stena Germanica
  another large boat: Santa Cruz de Tenerife
  skyline, including fortress on hilltop
  visit to fortress
  close-ups on cathedral
  Dorothy and young woman walk along sidewalk
  sidewalk and street scenes, including art shop
  Dorothy and others explore gardens?
  beach scenes, back to the small inlet with boats
  Dorothy on balcony overlooking inlet
  beach scenes, sunbathers and boats in inlet
  hotel pool and surrounding landscapes
  buildings and environs, some shot from car
  group rides by on horses
  airplane building?
  sign: "Bar Restaurante Pour Redo"
  pile of unknown construction elements
  view of ocean and surrounding landscape, including a shots of Dorothy with an unidentified man
  woman walks to hotel pool
  sidewalk and street scenes, including a number of signs in German, also Spanish
  field of trees
  small town streets captured from car
  building: "Casa Consistorial"
  unidentified church and environs
  ocean and coast
  buildings under construction
  gardens and natural landscapes
  hotel pool and environs, including hillside
  sunbathers and swimmers at the hotel pool, including Dorothy
  young girls walk down street in village
  wandering around streets of small village, shots of natural environs
  nuns in small village
  more wandering and shots of natural environs
  - Reversal original, Super 8, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (425 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 28:32) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 28:32) (Box 1)
- Travel Slides Series, 1959-1982, (4 boxes)
  During their travels, the Margolin family took many color photographs of their surroundings, and had them formatted into color film transparencies (slides). The slides are in good condition and are quite vivid, with images usually depicting buildings, native citizens, the Margolin family, street scenes, and typical tourist sights. Of particular interest are over 200 hundred slides from Russia taken in the 1960s, and many images of Israel from the 1960s and 1971. There are also pictures taken in Thailand in 1959 (the earliest in the series), and images from Florence, Italy, in 1968, two years following the devastating 1966 flood.
  The slides, arranged in chronological order and then alphabetically by country, were originally in carousels; their original projection sequencing has been preserved.
  - Bangkok, Thailand, 1959, (80 items) (Box 6)
  - French Riviera; Paris, France; Majorca and Barcelona, Spain, 1959, (69 items) (Box 6)
  - Italy, 1959 and 1967, (60 items) (Box 6)
    Includes Florence, Verona, Rome, Villa D'Este, and Como.
  - Greece, 1964, (74 items) (Box 6)
  - Israel, 1964, (80 items) (Box 6)
    A note on the carousel box for Tray 1 of 2 says "With Eleanor and Kal [?]."
  - USSR, 1964-1967, and Paris, undated, (91 items) (Box 6)
  - USSR, 1964-1967, (80 items) (Box 6)
    Includes Moscow and Leningrad. A note on the carousel box says "Excellent," and "Sound on tape."
  - Italy, 1964, (70 items) (Box 6)
    Includes Colombo, Naples, and Taormina.
  - Paris, France, 1964, (50 items) (Box 6)
  - Moscow, USSR, 1964 and 1967, (73 items) (Box 6)
    A handwritten note on the carousel box says "Sound on tape."
  - Japan, 1965, (76 items) (Box 6)
    Includes Fuji-Hakone National Park and Osaka.
  - Japan, 1965, (72 items) (Box 6)
    Includes Tokyo and Hiroshima.
  - Karachi; Hawaii; San Francisco, 1965, (66 items) (Box 6)
  - Kyoto, Dogo Spa, Japan, 1965, (69 items) (Box 6)
  - France, 1967, (73 items) (Box 6)
    Includes Paris and the Riviera.
  - Deauville, France, and Prague, Czechoslovakia, 1967, (79 items) (Box 7)
  - USSR, 1967, (80 items) (Box 7)
    Includes Yalta and Kiev.
  - Venice, Italy, 1967, (46 items) (Box 7)
  - Ireland, 1968, (82 items) (Box 7)
  - Italy, 1968, (61 items) (Box 7)
    Includes Milan and Rome.
  - Italy after the floods, 1968, (52 items) (Box 7)
    Includes Verona and Florence.
  - Italy, 1968 and 1972, (62 items (Box 7)
    Includes Sestri Levante, Montelatini, Portofino, and Lucca.
  - Rome, Italy, 1968, (76 items) (Box 7)
  - France, 1969 Nov., (77 items) (Box 7)
  - Spain, 1969 Nov., (60 items) (Box 7)
  - Spain, 1969, (92 items) (Box 7)
    Includes Granada, Seville, Madrid.
  - Gibraltar, Morocco, 1969, (126 items) (Box 7)
  - Capri, Italy, 1971 Sept., (105 items) (Box 7)
    Includes a few slides from Holland, 1971 Nov.
  - Africa, October 1971, (131 items) (Box 8)
    Includes Nairobi, Johannesburg, Capetown, and Durban.
  - Addis Ababa, Africa, October 1971, (76 items) (Box 8)
  - African Safari, October 1971 and Sofia, Bulgaria, 1975, (122 items) (Box 8)
    Includes Kenya, Tanzania, Zululand, and South Africa.
  - Israel, 1971 Oct., (142 items) (Box 8)
    Includes Jerusalem, Jericho, and Tel Aviv.
  - France, 1972, (91 items) (Box 8)
  - Italy, 1972, (2 folders, 140 items) (Box 8)
  - Munich, Germany; Zagreb, Yugoslavia, September/October 1972, (118 items) (Box 8)
  - Switzerland, 1972, (62 items) (Box 8)
    Includes Basel, Bern, and Geneva.
  - Switzerland, October 1972, (136 items) (Box 8)
    Includes Zermatt and Zurich.
  - Bucharest, Romania, Sofia, Bulgaria, and Budapest, Hungary, Sept.-Oct. 1975, (167 items) (Box 8)
  - France, 1975 Sept., (138 items) (Box 9)
    Includes Paris and Cannes.
  - London, England, 1976, (26 items) (Box 9)
  - Majorca and Amsterdam, Netherlands, 1976 July, (125 items) (Box 9)
  - Rhine River Cruise, July 1976, (67 items) (Box 9)
  - England, 1980 July, (129 items) (Box 9)
    Includes Bournemouth, Bath, and Stratford-upon-Avon.
  - Canadian Rockies, July 1981, (186 items) (Box 9)
  - Italy, 1982, (127 items) (Box 9)
  - Italy, 1982, (135 items) (Box 9)
  - Portugal and Italy, undated, (42 items) (Box 9)
  - Thailand and Paris, France, undated, (71 items) (Box 9)